C. Jordan Ball III Tel: 757-425-6200

Software / Web Developer

https://www.cjordanball.info https://github.com/cjordanball www.linkedin.com/in/cjordanball

JavaScript | NodeJS | React | Angular | Postgres | MongoDB

PROFILE

Former attorney turned programmer/web developer, with experience designing and building full-stack web applications within the NodeJS / Express environment. Highly skilled as a problem solver, ranked 1st or 2nd out of 125,000+ users on the coderbyte.com coding challenge website. A lifelong learner who combines a love of new technologies with a passion for digging deep into programming fundamentals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS (most developed are bolded)

Programming/Markup Languages: JavaScript (ES6), C, Go, HTML, CSS

Server-Side Frameworks: NodeJS, Express, Swagger

Front-End Frameworks: React/Redux, Angular, AngularJS, Bootstrap

Database: MongoDB / Mongoose, PostgreSQL / Sequelize / GraphQL

Charting: d3, Highcharts Testing: Mocha, Jasmine

AWS (EC2, S3, Route53, IAM, etc.), Git/GitHub, Bitbucket, Other:

Heroku, Webpack, Docker, Digital Ocean, Pivotal Tracker, J2IRA, agile development, Oracle Web Content Server

EXPERIENCE

Ball Web Development January 2018 to Present

Developer of online video course content for aspiring programmers/web developers. Solely responsible for all aspects of creation of two courses published on Udemy.com with perfect 5-Star ratings, JumpStart JavaScript and The Joy of RegEx!, including research and writing, scripting, filming, editing, and publication. Currently working on second module of web development course, JumpStart HTML & CSS.

Sept 2017 to Present

Collabera, Inc. Contract position working with Anthem scrum team responsible for user-facing portion of website of Fortune 50 company servicing millions of client accounts. Implementing designs in Angular, extensive writing of unit tests, working with Agile/SAFE team of developers, UX testers, and designers.

Shockoe August 2016 to May 2017

Software engineer creating web applications for large corporate clients. Lead development role in setting up application using Angular 4 framework enabling national retailer to manage inventory through mobile devices used by employees connected to company database. Lead front-end developer for application allowing employees to make reservations on corporate buses and for managers to supervise bus movement and ridership.

Lumiary May to July 2016 Contract position working as a developer for team updating front end of a customer data applica on currently employing a Backbone / Marionette framework. Creating new views to designer specifications as well as updating / debugging previously created views. Preparatory tasks to assist development of React / Redux app to replace current product.

CaseNex Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

Software developer on team designing and implementing large-scale commercial web-based application for the education market. Responsible for programming throughout the development stack, including basic design and layout of app components, implementing components using JavaScript / React / Flux, setting up routes in a REST routing structure using Swagger, writing PostgreSQL database gueries to react with application API, and distributing application state data as needed through a Flux event framework.

C. Jordan Ball III

Software / Web Developer



JavaScript | NodeJS | React | Angular | Postgres | MongoDB

EDCUATION (Degree Programs)

Manhattan School of Music

New York City

Bachelor of Music - Classical Guitar

Washington, DC

Georgetown University Law Center

New York City

Juris Doctor

New York University School of Law

LL.M. - Taxation

EDUCATION (Other)

General Assembly Seattle, WA

Web Development Immersive

November 2014 - February 2015

Full-time immersive coding boot camp, building web apps using MEAN stack and Ruby/Rails framework. Devoted approximately 80 to 90+ hours per week, including class sessions, homework, and building full-scale web applications. Graduated with extensive experience in designing and building web apps from front-end design to server-side/database.

Harvard University/edX

Verified Certificate

CS50 - Introduction to Computer Science

May 2015

Harvard's gateway computer science course. Although considered one of the most rigorous undergraduate courses at Harvard, it has proved so popular that in 2015 it was adopted by Yale as its introductory computer science course, via lectures streamed from the Harvard campus!

The first two-thirds of this twelve-week course are implemented in C, followed by sections addressing the Internet, web applications, and computer security, utilizing PHP, JavaScript, SQL, and other common web languages/frameworks. Graded assignments consist of nine problem sets plus a final project. Topics covered include: C syntax and programming structures; debugging techniques, particularly use of the gdb debugging tool; analysis and implementation of algorithms, with a focus on asymptoptic run times of common searching and sorting methods; data structures, including arrays, trees, tries, hash tables, linked lists, queues, and stacks; memory allocation and management, including use of pointers, heap, and stack memory; and file input/output, both dynamically and at the command line.

Code Fellows Seattle, WA

Foundations II: Javascript

October 2014

Survey of the fundamentals of JavaScript, including basics of functional, asynchronous programming, objectoriented JavaScript concepts, AJAX/JSON, use of libraries such as Lodash, Underscore, ¡Query, use of Git/GitHub.

Online Courses

Udemy, egghead.io, Treehouse Docker for DevOps Docker Technologies for DevOps and Developers React Native with Redux (in progress) Advanced React and Redux Modern React with Redux

C. Jordan Ball III

Software / Web Developer



JavaScript | NodeJS | React | Angular | Postgres | MongoDB

EDUCATION (Other, cont.)

NodeJS Basics

Understanding "this" in JavaScript

Online Courses (cont.)

Build Web Apps with React and Flux The Complete Developer's Guide to MongoDB Complete Guide to Angular4 Learn and Understand Angular Unit Tes ng Angular Webpack2: The Complete Developer's Guide ES6 JavaScript: The Complete Developer's Guide **NodeJS Basics** Learn and Understand NodeJS Build a Simple Dynamic Site with NodeJS NodeJS Codeless API Crea on: Up and Running with Swagge Use D3 to Build Interac ve Charts with JavaScript **Backbone Tutorial** Git Basics HTML / HTML Tables / HTML Forms **CSS Basics** CSS - Beyond the Basics Ruby Basics Java Basics **AJAX Basics**